Forgotten but not gone.
Blue Moon is a history, drama, comedy film directed by Richard Linklater.
On the evening of March 31, 1943, legendary lyricist Lorenz Hart confronts his shattered self-confidence in Sardi’s bar as his
former collaborator Richard Rodgers celebrates the opening night of his ground-breaking hit musical “Oklahoma!”.
Lorenz Hart, played by Ethan Hawke.
Elizabeth Weiland, played by Margaret Qualley.
Eddie, played by Bobby Cannavale.
Richard Rodgers, played by Andrew Scott.
Morty Rifkin, played by Jonah Lees.
Oscar Hammerstein II, played by Simon Delaney.
Blue Moon is a 2025 American biographical comedy-drama film directed by Richard Linklater and written by
Robert Kaplow, reportedly inspired by the letters of Elizabeth Weiland to Lorenz Hart.
The film stars Ethan Hawke, Margaret Qualley, Bobby Cannavale and Andrew Scott.
Its plot follows Hart as he reflects on himself on the opening night of
Oklahoma!, a new musical by his former colleague Richard Rodgers.
Blue Moon had its world premiere at the main competition of the 75th Berlin International Film Festival on
February 18, 2025, where it won the Silver Bear for Best Supporting Performance for Scott.
At the 83rd Golden Globe Awards, it was nominated for Best Motion
Picture – Musical or Comedy and Best Actor for Hawke.
At the 98th Academy Awards, Kaplow was nominated for Best
Original Screenplay and Hawke for Best Actor.
It was theatrically released in the United States by Sony Pictures Classics on
October 17, 2025, and received positive reviews from critics.
The film explores themes of lyricist, 1940s, intimate, egotistical, admiring.
The tone is lighthearted and emotional.